Unlimited space. Boundless suffering for the fallen souls
为无空间，为无量受业报之界
Uninterrupted time
无时间
Time
时间
I still remember my first arrest
我还记得我第一次抓那个犯人
It was December 12, 1980
那天是八零年十二月十二日
My partner and I were patrolling Hano Road
我与一位师兄在河内道巡膛
Shit was going down at New World Centre
收到通知，说新世界有事发生
We rushed over
我们马上赶去
A gang fight was taking place
到了现场，见几十人挥舞刀棍在械斗
About fifteen or so were already down
有十几个已经倒在地上
Lots of blood on the ground
地上很多血
Plus a severed hand, still holding a knife
我看见一只握着刀的断手
My partner told me to draw my piece
师兄叫我拔枪
I was a rookie so ! did what he told
我是个新丁，师兄说什么我便做什么
But before I could open the holster
我还没来得及打开枪袋
My partner already dropped
师兄已经跌倒在我面前
This kid stabbed a pipe into his belly
我见一个小子拿根铁管插进师兄的肚子
Blood gushed out of the sawed-off opening
血从铁管不停流出来
I didn't know what to think
我脑袋一片空白
I simply put all six of my bullets
只知道把六颗子弹
straight into that kid!
一下子全打在那小子的身上
I don't remember how many years he got
后来那小子判多少年我已记不起
But when I saw him again two years ago
两年前，我再遇上了他
he was boozing in a club, looking sharp
衣着光鲜，跟一伙人在喝酒
His buddies were all Kwun's goons!
这伙人，就是倪坤的手下
Evil prevails. Only the good die young
杀人放火金腰带，修桥补路无尸骸
I can barely recall my partner's face now
那个师兄的样子我已经很模糊
l regret
我很后悔
The six bullets weren't put into that kid's skull
那六检没打在那小子的头上
The world shouldn't be like this
世界不应该是这样
It's not the way to be, Sam
做人不应该是这样，琛
How long have you been around Tsim Sha Tsui?
你来尖沙咀多入?
Almost two years now
快两年了
Do you know why I haven't messed with you?
可知道这两年来我为何没有抓你?
‘Cause I am handsome!
我长得帅吧
Maybe so
可能是吧
‘Cause I think you're a decent guy
因为我党得你还像个人
I'd rather you be in charge
如果尖沙咀是你的地头，我就清闲多了
Forget about it
算了吧
You couldn't waste the kid even with six bullets
六颗子弹都没打死那小子
That makes you a decent guy, too. Right?
你是个好人
I don't want to be one
我宁愿不做这个好人
Kwun gave me everything, even my life
我这条命，是坤训给我的
If! turned against him
我若帮你对付他，我还算是个人吗?
I'd be despicable even in your eyes. Right?
你也会看不起我，对吧，?
I knew you'd say that
早就料到你是这样
Chivalry means little to the Ngai Family
为倪家做事，不能只讲义气
The Master often says
师傅常常告诫我
Retribution knows its time
因果报应总有时
Who knows how you and I will end up?
我也害怕最后几年不能和你吃饭
Time to work!
开工了
This early?
这么早?
I've got to eat! So do my boys!
我不吃，我的手下也要吃
Take the whole box
拿走吧
That's okay. Keep it
不要了，留给你
Don't worry about it! Just go!
不用收拾了，走吧
Want to use the back door?
要不要带你走后门?
Ain't no rules against schmoozing with cops
条例没规定不许跟警察做朋友
The front door's fine. Got used to it
我走正门吧，习惯了
Prat Avenue!
宝勒巷
Is Uncle Kwun in?
坤叔在吗?
Uncle Kwun! Someone's looking for you!
坤叔，有人找你
Bye, Mary
再见，玛莉姐
They say this American antique's got...
这部美国古董机
..sweet high, crisp middle and strong bass
有些傻瓜说它高音甜、中音准、低音劲
Bullshit!
真是胡说八道
180 grand!
要十八万多
Who can afford it in Hong Kong?
你说香港有多少人买得起?
Sit
坐
Only around ten thousand people can afford it
玩得起的人有一万多
Sam asked you to be a mole in the force
琛哥叫你去警察那边做卧底
If you don't like it, [ can talk to him
你要是不愿意，我跟他说一声
You're my boy after all
怎么说你也是我的人
It's fine with me
没事
Sure?
真的没事?
Positive
真的
Hand me that bag
帮有我拿手袋过来
Mary
玛莉姐
[ thought you'd been dreading it
我见你最近没精打采，还以为你不想去
Hide in Tuen Mun till things quiet down
这几天风声紧，回屯门一段时间吧
Stay fit for the Academy's new term
等警察学校开学
The money ! gave you, spend wisely
我给你那笔钱，省点用
You like the song?
你喜欢这首歌?
Yeah
已 下
It's yours
送给你
It won't sound as good on another player
但用别的机放，效果差很远
Someday I'll pick out a good one for you
以后赚到钱，我给你找一部好的
What? Don't like it?
怎么，不喜欢?
Not at all
不是
Sam gave you this watch, didn't he?
这表是琛哥送给你的?
None of your business
不关你事
Only you and I...
今晚的事…
..know about tonight
只有你和我知道
I don't want Sam to know
我不想琛哥知道
Why's that?
为什么?
Women are simple
女人很简单
A man treats me well, I'd do anything
只要男人好，我做什么都行
Now go home. I'm very busy tonight
你先回去吧，今晚会很忙
It's either you or me
出来混，不是你扁我就是我扁你
The boss said I would see blood today
师傅说我今天有血光之灾，我知道
The Mainlander kept asking...
表叔看得起我，老是问我
Got a Mercedes today, Keung?
强哥，今天有没有平治?
l said, "Of course." And here I am!
我当然说有，就出事了
Otherwise, I wouldn't be here with you
要不然，我用得着对着你?
Mainland girls in arms
我早在中国城搂北妞
That's for sure!
还用讲?
Hey, got a cigarette?
给我一口烟吧
I don't smoke
我不抽烟
Let's forget about it. My car's fine
算了吧，我的车也没事
See! She says it's all good
就是嘛，事主都说没事了
Dressed all dandy
你看你…
Don't want any trouble, do you?
斯斯文文，当然不想搞事
Look at me. All beaten up by you
你看我，给你打成…
Who do you think the judge would believe?
你说，上到法庭法官会信谁? 你自己想想
bet you guys never go to Tsim Sha Tsui East, huh?
还有，你们不去尖东吗?
Know who I am? I'm Keung!
可知道我是谁? 我是傻强
Sam's top dog. Del Piero's boy
韩琛的头马，迪露的头马
I'll kick your ass every time I see you
怎么样? 当然是见一次打一次
And you can count on that
还用讲?
How about calling an ambulance, sir?
警官，叫救护车吧
Look at all the blood!
你看，都流血了
Have them bring 500 cc Type O. It's rare!
多准备500毫升0型血，很难找的
Shut up!
0什么?
Wait till we're back to the station
跟我回警局慢慢解释
Why do I have to go to the station?
干么要我上警局?
l only stole a piece of junk, sir!
警官，我只是偷部车而已
Just shut up!
闭嘴吧! 还说
Does that deserve an OCTB beating?
回去还不让你们扁?
Don't you know you're just a cadet?
你知不知道自己是学警?
And you are expected to get a medal this year
还说今年会考全班第一
Don't ever let Yip know about this!
不要让叶校长知道
Happy birthday!
生日快乐
What's there to be happy about?
什么快乐?
Ten years in the Academy. A rustic hell
在警校蹲了十年，见的树比人还多
You even managed to get me out
你都能把我弄出去
Your case's now ancient history
你的案子已经隔那么长时间
Get yourself out
把自己也申调出去吧
So what if the Commissioner's Chinese now?
虽然现在由华人担任警务处长
Still six more years till the hand-over
但要等老外都走了，还要六年
I'll be 48 by then!
那时我四十八了
Might as well train a few good cops here!
不如在学校多教几个好警察
The world is yours after 1997!
九七年以后，属于你们了
27149! Cheers!
27149，乾杯…
Yan
阿仁
Been beeping the whole day
响了一整天
How come you don't call back?
怎么不回电话?
Girlfriend?
女朋友?
Cheers, sir! Cheers!
乾杯，长官            赣杯…
Just leave me alone!
走啊!
It's none of my business ! don't want to know a thing
不关我事，我也不想知道
Go! Leave me alone!
走啊! 你给我走啊
Law
罗鸡
What do you want?
干什么?
My father just passed way
我爸爸刚去世
It was his wish to inform his children...
他生前曾吟只
when something bad happened to him!
如果他过世，就要通知所有子女
Sorry to have bothered you!
不好意思，打扰了
Stop watching TV! Eat first, Negro!
黑鬼，看什么电视，吃饭吧
l wonder what they have on Kwun's death
坤地死了，看电视台有什么消息
Did you do it, Ching?
文揉，这事你干的?
I've got a big mouth. Had ! done it...
我嘴巴大，要是我干的
.. you would've heard about it!
时就通天只
Ask Wah and Gandhi
你问国华，甘地
When Kwun died, I was in Macau
坤叔死的时候，我在澳门谈生意
Everybody knows!
大家都知道
But I bet his kids think I did it
他的子女一定算在我头上
[ain't scared of nothing
我甘地才不怕
The eldest son's a doctor The youngest a brat
他的大儿子当医生，小儿子游手好闲
The daughter's married for ages
女儿早已出嫁
Only the middle son's running the show
只剩下二儿子看着他的生意
If they go too far, I'll show them!
如果他们太过份，我随时收拾他们
We failed to protect Kwun. It's our fault!
我们没有好好保护坤叔，是我们不对
That's enough, Uncle John
三叔
Dad used to say
葡爸常说
What goes around comes around
出来跑，迟早要还的
It came later than expected already
他现在才出事，算是赚了
Wah, Ching, Negro and Gandhi
你们能猜到，国华、文皇…
Guess what those four are thinking?
黑鬼、甘地他们四个，现在在想什么?
Thank you. Thank you all!
麻烦你们，谢谢
How's mom doing, sis?
姐，妈妈没事吧?
She's fine. Been sleeping
没事，早就睡着了
Bring some cigs to the morgue for dad
她吟哇，买几和包香烟送去克房给和爸爸
I'll go get them
我去买
B Team, watch Tak Shing Street
B组负责把守德诚街两边街口
C Team, watch the Austin Road exit...
0组守着财务公司那剧大厦
..Of that financial building
在柯士甸道这边的出入口
It has two exits
这幢大厦有两个出入口
One on Tak Shing Street. One on Austin...
一个在德诚街，一个在柯…
Sorry
对不起
Hello?
了腿?
Something this big, why didn't you call?
这么重大的事，为什么不先告诉我?
l called everybody the minute it happened!
一出事我就通知所有人了
Kwun's boys can't sit still for sure
倪坤一死，下面的一定坐不住
Shit will hit the fan tonight!
今晚尖沙咀一定有事发生
It's the 14th already. You know that?
你知道，今天十四号
The 14th. Time to pay the Ngai Family
今天十四号，大家都要向倪家交数
I'm the youngest here
这里我最小
So let me be the jackass
不中听的话我先说吧
I'm not paying the Ngai's any more
这个月起，坤叔的数我不再给
What do you three think?
你们三位大哥意思怎样?
Inspector Wong
黄警官
What's up?
怎么样?
What're your men doing outside Wah's building?
你的人在国华楼下干吗呀?
Not a good day for chit chat
今天先不谈
Are you into something?
你搞什么?
Fine, fine. Next time
行，改天再说
What's the occasion?
这么热闹?
Come on. Where's my seat?
来，给我位子
Only if you're here for the food
你若是来吃饭，我们会很高兴
All other businesses have to wait
其它事，过了今晚再说
The food. It's all about the food
吃! 吃吧
Tonight's gonna be the shit!
今天晚上肯定不简单
Let the Big Four do their things
没办法，等他们四个老大办完事
We'll deal with the aftermath
我们才收拾残局吧
Don't let them start fighting
不能让他们打起来
Or you'll see bodies
一打起来，非出人命不可
What? Not satisfied?
怎么样? 不满意?
You know the rule. Pick a card
照旧，抽牌决定
Okay. Higher points win
好呀，我们比大
Come on!
来呀
There's nothing left to talk about
还找我干么?
What's up, Hau?
怎么样，阿孝?
Wah
国华
Nothing much
没什么
Heard you're planning a casino in Macau
我知道你最近在澳门谈赌场生意
I've got the government in my pocket
政府方面我已谈有了
How about a joint venture?
看看你有没有兴趣一起搞
Uncle Kwun's dead
坤叔死了
I'm not in the mood
我什么兴趣都没有
lsee
那倒是
The Macau trip wasn't all business
你到澳门不单是谈生意
I know you had fun with Gandhi's wife
我知道你还跟甘地的老婆玩得很开心
Sorry, but I can't let go of my casino in Macau
不好意思，我澳门的赌场不能放手
Gotta go
我先走
What are Sam's people doing?
韩琛那帮人在搞什么?
I know Wah paid up
我知道国华已经交数了
Don't change the subject
你少讲废话
Tell me something I don't know!
讲我不知道的事，好吗?
Call me when you get your shit straight!
你搞清楚再打给我
Hau took care of Wah in ten minutes
阿孝上去不到十分钟就搞定了国华
The Big Four are having a tough time
我看今晚那四个老大很难搞定他
Hau took out a million's worth of coke
我的线人说倪永孝拿了一百万毒品出来
What?
怎么?
Mafia road block or what?
黑社会封路?
[ don't know why Wah paid up, Hau
倪生，我不知道国华为何要交数
But I ain't gonna negotiate
总之，我没得商量
I don't plan to negotiate, either
我没打算跟你商量
Pass the phone to Negro
你叫黑鬼来听
Hey, Negro
黑鬼
Don't know why he calls you from my hood
我也不晓得他怎会在我地头打电话给你
What's up, Hau?
怎样，阿孝?
I'm with Gandhi all the way
甘地说的就等于我说的
He's not paying, neither will I!
他不交，我也不交了
Heard you and Gandhi have been tight
没什么，听说最近你跟甘地来往甚密
The heroin you two smuggled got robbed
还一起运了一批海洛英，但被人动走了
Lost several millions each, right?
每人损失了几百万，对吧?
Luckily ! found the stuff in your warehouse
幸好，我在你的仓里捡回来
Want me to hand it back to Gandhi now?
要不要我现在交给甘地的人?
What's he talking about?
他说什么?
Among the Tsim Sha Tsui Big Fives...
尖沙咀五帮人
Wah and Negro paid up
国华、黑鬼都交数了
Counting Sam, that's 3 to 2
加上琛哥，三比二
I'm the youngest here. Gotta pay!
这里我最小，不交不行
See ya!
二位，告辞
Don't think too much. Cheers!
别想那么多，乾杯
Pay my share for me!
帮有我交了倪家的数
Mr. Ngai went to eat, Inspector Wong
黄警官，倪先生说他去吃宵夜了
A bit late for chowing, don't you think?
倪先生，这么晚才吃饭?
My dad always came here after work
答爸多年来下班后就来这儿吃宵夜
l have to keep up the ritual
我今晚办完事，照例来光顾一下
Want to join us?
怎样，有没有兴趣? 一起吧
It's your seat from now on. Must be tough
看来这位子将由你来坐，泣苦了
Not at all
哪里
You guys worked all night for nothing
你们今晚劳师动众
Now that's tough
但毫无收获，不是更辛苦?
Well done, Hau
阿孝，你今晚表现真不错
Hope you can keep it up
我希望你一直这样
Don't let it turn into a tragedy. Let's go
我不想看到以后有什么事情发生，走
What did you say?
你不想什么?
We want to celebrate
我们想开香槟庆祝
Kwun's dead
倪坤死了
Want me to pop one for you?
要我给你多开一瓶吗?
What?
怎么?
Want to mess with cops?
你想打警察?
Officers!
两位警官
The Ngai's are in mourning
今天倪家已经少了一人
What more do you want?
还想怎样?
Let's go
走吧，走
Sam
琛哥
Dad used to operate street gambling here
和葡爸以前开小周档
Started out as...
从几和毛钱小生意
a dime-and-nickel business
做到现在…
Now who doesn't know his name?
整个尖沙咀没有人不认识他
He often said
他常说出来跑…
What goes around comes around
迟早要还
And now he's...
想不到今天…
I'll always remember this day
我永远会记住今天
It's all good, honey. Want some snacks?
老婆，没事了，要不要宵夜?
Good to hear that. Just come home
没事就好，我回家等你
An officer has to have a clean background
当警察一定要身家清白
Though you cut your ties with the Ngai's...
虽然你跟母亲姓，一直与倪家没来往
..you still share the same father with Hau
但你和倪永孝是同一个父亲
That means you lied on your application
已经违反了虚报个人背景的校规
l have but to let you go
我一定要开除你
But before you leave...
但你走之前
..go see "Mr. Wrong Socks" first
先见一见刚才穿错袜子的那个人
Still want to be a cop?
还想不想当警察?
Can I still?
我还可以吗?
Only if you can give me a good reason
只要你给我一个好的理由
l want to be a righteous person
我想做好人
If you want to be a cop...
想当警察
..then lend me a hand. Simple as that
除了帮有我的忙，你没别的选择
You pick me 'cause I'm Hau's brother right?
你选我，是因为我是阿孝的弟弟?
When the time comes will you arrest him yourself?
如果有需要，你会不会亲手捉他?
How do I start?
那我怎样开始?
Brace
琶下
You okay?
还可以吗?
Hanging in there?
挺得住吗?
3G What's wrong?
怎么了?
Does it still hurt?
打得你好痛呀?
My dad passed away today
我爸今天死了…
He was so good to me
他最疼我的
l asked the officer...
我去求长官…
..if ! could go to his funeral
能不能让我出去买个饭拜他
The officer said...
长官就对我说…
Know what it means to be a prisoner?
你知不知道什么叫坐牢?
It means you're not allowed
坐牢就是，就算你老爸死了
even to attend your father's funeral
也不能让你出去拜
Don't you know that?
你明不明白?
Get out of here!
走吧
Come on. Stop that
别这样
Time
时间
Are you nuts?
你有病?
You sent Yan to be a mole?
你派阿仁去做卧底
Don't you know Hau's his half-brother?
你知不知道阿孝是他亲哥哥?
So what?
那又怎样?
Bring me his file!
把他的资料给我
So you're playing the boss now, huh?
你不是升了官就给我脸色看吧?
You damn well know you the files are classified
你知道警队机密档案是不可随便泄露
I treat you like a bro. Is this what I get?
我把你当兄弟，你跟我说这个?
If you're a real bro, stop asking!
你当我是兄弟就不要问
It's okay
没事的
Calm down!
冷静点
Speak slowly!
慢慢说吧
She had an abortion!
她把孩子打掉只
It's no big deal. Just a baby
那有什么，生小孩嘛
You can always have another one
打掉了再生一个，是这样嘛
I've been with you for four years
我和你一起四年了
And I've bailed you out tons of times
上警察局保释你也有十几次
One minute we're dining with my folks...
跟我家人吃饭…
..the next you'll be in a gang fight
你可以突然跑去砍人
I don't want our baby to grow up like you
我不想孩子将来也这样
Do you understand?
你明不明白?
Why so uptight?
见到我就这么拘遵?
No, nothing
没有
Uncle John says you're doing well
听三叔说，你干得不错
Ever thought about helping the family out?
有没有想过回家帮忙?
[know you want to keep a distance from the Ngai's
我明白你不想让人知道你和倪家的关系
But we're blood brothers. It's a fact
但我们是亲兄弟，这是事实
It's my daughter's birthday this Sunday
星期天我女儿生日
You're invited
我想你回家一趟
You really hate talking to me, huh?
你真的不喜欢跟我说话?
No
不是
Promoted already? Soon you'll be a superintendent
转眼就升职，快要升警司了?
Might as well become a full time cop
全职当差好了
Sam's kidding. Go ahead give me a smile
琛哥跟你开玩笑，快笑一笑
Thanks for your intel these couple years
这两年全靠琛哥给我情报
When you were still a rookie...
以前你是小角色，就让你抓些小鱼虾子
l helped you catch some small potatoes
帮有我扫扫场，扫走那些咎鬼蛇神
It's about time you caught some big shots
现在你升了职，要抓就要抓些高级的
How about catching me?
要不给让你来抓我吧
Why so dirty? Or you can catch this hot chicks
这么脏” 要不抓个美女
What're you doing?!
你干什么呀?
What a hot hootchie mama!
哪有这么漂亮的女人?
Your man must be one good-looking bastard
你男人一定很帅，不然怎配得上你?
It's you! Who else?
不就是你嘛
Gotta go
走了            又走?
Gotta go meet Mr. Ngai
约了倪先生，要干活呀
Sam's so good to you!
琛哥…对你真好
But he's not good to himself
可惜他对自己不好
It's been four years
四年了
He could be in charge now
本来他可以做老大
But he gave everything to the Ngai's Already?
但他全都给了那姓倪的
Now the Ngai Family's all big and bad
现在没人敢碰姓倪的
Hau must've figured it out
那件事，阿孝一定找人算账
For the past four years
这四年来…
I haven't been sleeping well
我一直都睡不好
Don't worry, Mary
放心吧，玛莉姐
l won't let anything happen to you
我不会让你有事的
Words, words, words
你说得出要做得到
I promise
一定
Toss it up!
把球扔过去
Two days ago, a real estate agent came
前两天，有个地产经纪来看房子
Guess how much he offered?
你们犹他开出什么价?
One hundred sixty million!
一亿六，一亿六二万
What's wrong with Hong Kong? Tell me!
你说香港发生了什么事?
When my dad bought it
我记得和葡爸买这里的时候是…
it was 9 million...280 thousand
九百…二十八万
What a world!
这是什么世界?
Moving, Mr. Ngai?
侃先生，要换房子吗?
1997 is approaching. Time to emigrate
没什么…九七了要移民
No big deal
没什么大不了?
Communication's easy these days
现在一切都很方便
We're just a phone call away
有事打个电话过来就行了
I'm just worried about the phone bill
我也这么想，但又怕交不起电话费
The phone company's greedy, you know
你们知道，电话公司都很无良
I've discussed it with mom
我和妈妈商量过
Our businesses are on the right track
我们倪家生意都上了轨道
You guys helped out so much in the past
你们也帮忙打理生意很长时间了
don't want to be ungrateful
我们不想让人觉得我们不负责任
l want to split the business up...
所以打算走了以后，把这盘生意…
among you guys
分给你们几位
Treat it as a gift or a retirement fund
当是感谢也好，公积金也好
Let's eat! Take whatever you want!
吃吧，喜欢什么拿什么
We should hang out like this more often
以后有空要常聚首，像今天这样，多好
Mr. Ngai
倪先生
Are you leaving for real?
你真的要走?
After you're gone, hell will break loose!
你走了会乱的
You're a Buddhist, aren't you, Sam?
阿琛，你信佛吧?
Easy to start. Hard to let go
拿起容易，放下难
I'm letting go. Be happy for me
我今天放得下，你该蔡我高兴
Cocaine will be the future
往后一定是可卡因的世界
Those four ship it in small bags from S. America
他们四个从南美一小包一小包运过来
Small-timers!
成不了气候
I've closed a deal with the Thais
我和泰国那边谈好了
You'll have the monopoly
以后让你独家进口
You'll be the top dog. Leader of the pack
到时候你是大庄家，谁都听你的
Go to Thailand and wrap up the logistics
迟些你过泰国办好手续，便可回来开始
You plan to get rid of those four?
你打算干掉他们四个?
Move closer to the right, please
右边的靠近一点
Yan
永仁
Come join the family portrait
过来合照吧
Stand next to me!
站这儿
l haven't been around much these two years
其实这两年我很少留在香港
It's rare to spend time...
所以今天…
.. With the whole family like this
难得一家人…共聚天伦
Your siblings are in legit businesses
姐姐，哥哥和弟弟都做了正行
It's time you helped out the family
所以你应该回家帮忙
Everything dad did was for the family
以前葡爸做每件事都是为了这个家
I did the same
我也是
Hope you will, too
我希望你也是
A deal's coming up next week Come with me
下星期有个买卖，我想你和我一起去
I'll call you
到时候我联络你
I think he's taking the deal seriously
这交易一定很重要，所以他要亲自去
He'll go in person next Wednesday
日期是下星期三，十四号
The 14th... Kwun's memorial
十四号…倪坤的死忌
Hau wants to whack the Big Four
他想杀那四个老大
Why does he send Sam away?
那他为什么要支开韩琛?
Don't know. Sam should be of help to him!
不知道，韩琛理应帮得了他
Unless he wants to kill Sam also!
他想连韩琛也杀?
I've been following you around for days!
我跟踪你们好几天了
I'm your superior after all
不管怎么说，我也是你们上司
I want to know what your plan is
我想知道你们下一步要干什么
The Ngai's are your family
姓倪的是你的家人
Do you really know what you're doing?
你知道你现在在做什么?
Sirl
长官
Good
好
Give me a salute
敬个礼给我看看
I've booked a table. Care for dinner?
订了位子和你吃饭，一会儿有空吗?
Do I look good in my cap?
戴帽子好看吗?
Looking good?
好不好看
What'll you do in Thailand in that outfit?
穿成这样，到泰国搞什么?
Have some shark fin
没什么
A massage. Get two whores for a threesome
吃鱼翅，按按摩，再来个一王两后
That's for sure
还用说?
Honey!
老公
What?
怎样?
Why didn't you tell me about your trip?
你去泰国为什么不告诉我?
It's a business trip! Not for fun!
办正事呀，你以为去打泰源吗?
Don't worry. I'll behave
放心，不乱搞
Hau plans to whack Wah and those guys
倪永孝要收拾国华他们呀
l know
我知道
But do you know you're his target too?
那你知不知道他也想收拾你?
Nonsense! How can that be?
别听人乱说，怎么会呢?
Just wait for me at the airport!
总之你别管，你在机场等我
Time to board, Sam!
琛哥，上机了
That's all 1 can do for now
我可以做的就这么多
Call Sam again when the plane lands
等阿琛下了机再打给他
I'm going to kill Hau tonight
我今晚就要杀掉阿孝
Don't do anything rash!
你别乱来
I'm not being rash!
我不是乱来
Four years ago...
我只是记得四年前…
.. you told me to kill Kwun
是你叫我杀掉倪坤的
So what? Want to blackmail me now?
那怎么样? 你想要肋我?
I'm not blackmailing you
我不是要肋你
We simply passed the point of no return!
我们现在都不能回头了
I'll send everybody away
到时候我调走所有人
Tonight's operation's top secret
今天晚上行动要绝对保密
We're divided into three teams
我们分三个组
Team A watches here
A组，把住这个出口
Team B here
B组，在这个出口
Wait for my order before doing anything
没我的命令不准行动
Team C follows the target until...
0组一直跟踪目标人物，直到…
Nobody told me about the date change!
改了日期干么不通知我?
You know Hau changes his mind all the time
我早就说过，阿孝这人很难捉摸
You think Yan's the only mole?
你以为只有你会在他身边安插人?
My man's been undercover for seven years!
我有个卧底跟了他七年
Where's the deck of cards?
那副牌呢?
We'll run the show together tonight
让你一次，我们一起决定
Let's go!
出发
Sir
长官
How are you?
你好吗?
Don't move...
别动…
Hau
阿孝
Zipping it till your lawyer gets here?
你非要等到律师来才开口?
Come on, cooperate with us!
合作点吧
In fact, l appreciate your cooperation
别这么说，我谢谢你合作才对
Are you speaking Zen, Mr. Ngai?
倪先生，你说话那么深奥
I don't get it
没人明白的
Dad used to say...
葡爸常说
.. the way things work in the streets...
出来跑，无论做过什么…
... what goes around always comes around
迟早要还
He died four years ago. It's about time
他死了四年，今天是时候了
The stove's hot enough now
老板，贮炉可以用了
She's here, boss
老板，来了
You're here now
你现在人都在这儿了
What can you swing?
还可以做得了什么?
Wait and see
不知道
Got it! Sir
长官，查到了
The two foreigners are private eyes
原来那两个洋人是私家侦探
Honey! Where are you?
老公，你在哪里?
Thailand, of course
我在泰国嘛
Come back right away!
你快回来
Are you nuts? Why should I come back?
神经病! 我回来干什么?
Don't ask questions! Just come back!
你别管那么多，快点回来
Hau wants you dead!
阿孝要找人杀你呀
Nonsense! I'm working for him as we speak!
胡说，我正帮他做事呀
Listen to me!
你听我说
I killed Kwunt
倪坤…是我杀的
You've got a VCR?
你们有录像机吗?
Isn't it good?
好看吗?
What an awesome show!
非常好看
Take care. Run if you have to
小心，出事先走
What did Hau say?
阿孝有什么说?
Sam. Sunny!
阿琛                      举尼
Mr. Ngai told me to take good care of you!
倪先生叫我好好招呼你
Four years ago...
我只是记得四年前…
.. you told me to kill Kwun
是你叫我杀掉倪坤的
So what? Want to blackmail me now?
那怎么样? 你想要肋我?
I'm not blackmailing you
我不是要肋你
We simply passed the point of no return!
我们现在都不能回头了
I'll send everybody away
到时候我调走所有人
l hired Alan and Johnson...
阿伦和钟逊
..to investigate my father's murder
是我请来帮有我查杀和葡爸的凶手
Who would've known? The police conspired...
想不到你们有些警务人员…
to murder my father
知法犯法
A law-abiding citizen
杀害我爸爸这样的良好市民
SP Luk
陆长官
Isn't that an officer in the video?
画面里那个算不算是警察?
Whether to nail him or not...
怎样做，抓不抓他…
. that's up to you
你自己决定
What a good show!
真的很好看
You're so friggin’ photogenic
你好上镜
Four years ago...
四年前…
How much did Sam's woman pay you?
你们收了韩琛的女人多少钱?
Give me another chance, Mr. Ngai
倪先生，给次机会吧
I gave them a chance four years ago
四年前，我给了他们机会
They didn't take it
他们没有要
If l give you a chance
如果我今天给你机会
Are you going to take it today?
你要不要?
You've been with us for seven years now
你在我倪家七年了
You're a cop
你是警察
We're the bad guys
我们是黑社会
Time to accept our fates
各安天命吧
You can't blame me
别怪我
Your Inspector Wong killed my dad
因为你们的黄长官杀了我爸和区
Any words from Sam?
有没有琛哥的消息?
He said he was fine
他说他没事
He asked you to wait for him here
叫你在这儿躲几天，等他回来
Where're your folks?
你的家人了呢?
All emigrated
都移民了
You didn't go with them?
你不去?
Let's go, Sam! We got rid of the Thais
琛哥快走! 没有人追来
Let's go!
快走吧
You know you're not going to make it
你知道你跑不了的
l know
我知道
My girl's in danger in Hong Kong
我女人在香港很危险
Please help me
我求你帮帮有我
Why should I?
我为什么要帮你?
‘Cause I'll help you whack your boss
因为我帮你除掉你老大
I Know you want to be in charge
我知道你很想坐那个位子
Moreover
还有
I've been treating you as a pal
我一直当你是我好朋友
Don't believe him, Sam! Don't!
别信人他:! 琛哥，别信他
Get lost!
走开
Don't believe him! Get lost!
别信他咱                走开
Sorry, Sam
对不起，琛哥
Are you here to arrest me?
来抓我?
If you're going to kill Hau
你现在要去杀阿孝
I will
我就抓你
Then there's nothing to talk about
那就是没商量了
l spoke with my superiors
我跟上头已经说好
They're with you all the way this time
他们说这次…一定支持你
How?
怎样支持?
[ conspired in murder!
我教唆杀人呀
Even the Brits agree that...
就连上面那些老外都说
..we can't let the triads break us
不可以让黑社会胡来
The whole department's behind you
现在警察局的人都支持你
Good enough?
你说你够不够?
Where's your deck of cards?
牌呢?
The higher points win
这次我们比大
Come back with me to the department
听我的，跟我回警局开会
The key!
钥匙
Forget it. l screwed up
算了，我还不够粮吗?
No need to drag everyone down with me
别连累人家了
We found this deck in our first outing together
这副牌是我们第一次合作捉老于
You've been keeping it all this time
你留下来的
I knew that all along
我一直都知道
I've let you get your way in the past
这么多年，我让你好几次了
It's your turn to listen for once
你该听我一次吧
We're like brothers
我们是兄弟
Think I'm just gonna be a spectator?
你有事我可以不管吗?
Law's my snitch in the Ngai Family
罗继是我安插进去的卧底
He hasn't contacted me for days
他已经几天没跟我联络了
Neither has Yan!
阿仁也是
The key!
钥匙
Help!
出来呀
Help! Get some help!
帮忙呀…帮忙呀
Why did you lie to me?
你为什么骗我?
I didn't!
没有咱
Something happened to Sam!
琛哥出了事
I told you I was a simple woman
我跟你说过，我是个很简单的女人
l have to do something for my husband
现在我老公出事，我怎样也得做点事
I'm going to Thailand
我要去泰国
Please don't go!
你不去行吗?
Forget it! You don't have to follow us anymore
算了，你就当没跟过我
[ mean, I don't want you to go
我是说，我叫你别去行不行?
You've been with Sam for years
其实，你跟琛哥那么多年…
Has it occurred to you...
有没有想过…
Maybe Sam's dead!
琛哥已经死了
What did you say?
你说什么?
l can take care of you
我可以照顾你
What're you doing?
你干什么?
I don't want you to go!
我不想你走
You're out of line!
造反啦?
Listen up!
我告诉你
I'm your boss's woman!
我是你大哥的女人
Don't let me see your face again!
以后别再让我见到你
She will go to the airport tonight...
今晚她会去机场……
Hello? Hello?
咀? 喂?
I killed Kwunt
倪坤是我杀的
Aman treats me well
只要男人好
I'd do anything
我做什么也行
Time
时间
File number 103142
档案编号103142
About Inspector Wong conspiring in murder
有关黄志诚督察教唆谋杀案
This is the 11th internal hearing
现由三位高级警官作第十一次内部聆讯
do you have any question?
你有没有问题?
No...
没有…
No
没有
An inspector should possess leadership skills
成为营察，必须具备领导才能
Mr. Lau
刘警官
you joined as a police constable
你现为普通警员
Could you tell the promotion board
可和否告诉评选会
why you deserve to be promoted?
提升你为督察的理由?
Of course
可以
On April 11, 1995...
一九九五年四月十一日
The department received this tape
投诉科收到这盒带子
Accusing you of conspiring in a murder
指控你串谋黑帮，合谋杀人
l confess, sir
我认罪，长官
It's already 1997
现在是一九九七年了
Before the 1st of July
在七月一日之前
If we don't receive your PO assessment report
如果我们还未通过你的升级报告
Do you still think you can be promoted?
你认为你仍有机会晋升吗?
In Chinese, there is a saying
中国人有和名话
With a new king come new followers
一朝天子一朝臣
So, I guess we will have to start all over again
所以，我想我要重头开始
What happened to you?
你为什么会变成这样?
If I told you...
如果我告诉你
..that the evidence couldn't stand
这些所谓的证据都不成立
would you like to start over?
你想不想重头开始?
I'm sorry. I broke the law
对不起，我犯了法
What do you think of the police force's morale after 1997?
你对九七后的警队士气有何看法?
Chinese people are sentimental
中国人重感情
I hope the law will continue to back me up
我相信法律会继续支持我们
But, I strongly believe in myself, sir!
但我有信心，我相信自己
I'm grateful to all of you
各位怎样对我，我知道
But I've got no confidence left. I lost!
但我没有信心，我已经输了
What about Luk then?
那阿昌又怎样?
Can you face him if you give up now?
你党得现在这样做，对得起他吗?
The war's not over
这场仗还没打完
We all want a closure to this incident
我们每人都希望这件事有个交待
Hong Kong is not run by the Ngai Family
我们想外面知道，香港不是由姓倪的来管
Here's a file from the Interpol
这里有份国际刑警档案
Read it before your make up your mind
你看完再作决定吧
Ever been to a funeral in Thailand?
有没有去过泰国的丧礼?
A few months ago...
几个月前…
[had one for my wife
我为我老婆办了一个
The monks chanted for three full days
请了些大师给她哈了三天三夜的经
I didn't shed a single tear
这三天…我没流过一滴眼泪
On the day of the burial...
没想到出殡那天
.. they left the casket in the living room
尾工把棺材抬到我家客厅里
l was mad
当时我很愤怒
l wanted to beat them up
很想打人
The monk told me
大师就对我说
it's a tradition in Thailand
这是泰国人的习俗
The deceased...
死去的人…
As long as we keep her company...
需要我们陪伴她
for a little while longer
过一段时间
she can attain eternal peace
她就可以安息了
But I asked the monk
但我对大师说
what if my wife was not in the coffin?
我老婆不在棺材里
Could she still attain eternal peace?
她可不可以安息?
Sorry about your wife
嫂子的事，对不起
The monk placed his hand here
大师马上按住我这里
He said, "No problem
他说: 没问题…
Your wife's here."
你太太在你这儿就行了
And here's exactly...
刚巧这里…
..where the Thais shot me!
就是泰国人打我一枪的地方
So I told myself
我对自己说
I've passed the point of no return
我是不能回头了
Testifying against Hau could be dangerous
这次回香港指证倪永孝，很危险
I believe in you. You're so handsome
你这么帅，我有信心
Haven't heard that for ages. Thanks
很久没人跟我说这和句话了，谢谢
What's your plan?
你有什么打算?
Just trying to do my best
尽力而为吧
No big deal. It's my job
没什么，工作嘛
I'll leave Hong Kong when it's all over
解决这件事后，我会离开香港
You've changed
你变了
Baby
宝贝
You diluted the coke, didn't you?
这货你调稀了?
Got anything to say?
没话说了?
Take it all then!
你把它全吸掉
Don't go too far, Yan
阿仁，别这么绝
It'd break the boys' morale
让小的看见，哪有心情干活?
Mr. Ngai asked me to be in charge here
是倪先生叫我做的
Don't like it? Drive him to the hospital!
你不喜欢可以送他上医院
No matter what
无论他们做错什么
they're elders after all
他们还是长辈
You've got lots to learn from them
你以后还有很多东西要跟他们学
Uncle John will retire in a few years
三叔再做几年就退休了
You know what I mean?
你明白我的意思吧?
I don't need any hiccups now
我不想这时候有什么事发生
The Labor Athletic Association has a formal...
今晚劳工体育会请吃回归宣
.. for us Political Consultative candidates
我们所有政协候选人都会去
If everything works out
如果我这次成功
our family will no longer live in shadows
我们倪家以后就可以抬起头来做人
Mr. Cheung
张先生
Mr. Ngai
倪先生
How are you? Good. Good
你好                      你好…
When Solicitor Hung mentioned you
我听洪大律师提起过你
I didn't believe him
我还不太相信呢
You're amazingly young, Mr. Ngai
倪先生，你看看，你真是年青有为啊
What's your Zodiac?
属什么?
Ox
生
The Year of the Ox
属牛
Ox's good
属咎好啊
Director Chan likes young people
陈主任最喜欢跟年轻人打交道
I'll introduce you later. Thanks
待会儿给你介绍介绍                谢谢
Really?
是吗?
Director Chan said he hated the triads
主任对我说过，他最痛恨黑社会
That's right, SP Leung
梁长官，对了
Mr. Ngai's been invited to consult the police
倪先生刚刚受邀请，到警察投诉部当顾问
Really? Congratulations!
是吗? 恭喜…
Where do you golf these days, Chan?
老陈，最近多到哪里打球?
Zhong Shan Onsen
中山温泉
What's your handicap these days?
中山? 你现在打多少杆?
How are you? My name's Ngai...
你好，小姓倪
Mr. Ngai Wing-Hau
倪永孝先生
I'm Mr. Ngai's solicitor
我是倪先生的律师
Tonight's a celebration for HK's hand-over
今天是劳工体育会的回归酒会
All other businesses can wait
有事酒会后再说行不行?
What if l say no?
我说不行
Got any problem with that?
有没有问题?
Mr. Ngai
倪先生
You're a suspect
现在怀疑你
in several murder cases in 1995
与一九九五年多宗谋杀案有关
You're under arrest
这张是拘捕令
This is your arrest warrant
现在要拘捕你
Everything you say
你所说的话
will be recorded...
我们会用纸和笔记下
and could be used as evidence against you
将来作为呈堂证供
Do you have any question?
有没有问题?
No
没有
I looked through their files
我看过他们的资料
The murder charges won't stand
谋杀罪名一定不能成立
But your being a triad boss...
不过，身为三合会的龙头
That one will stick
我无法帮你脱罪
The unions and the political parties called
三哥，刚才几个工会和政党打电话来
They want to withdraw their invitations
说想收回他们回归晚会的帖子
Words from the HK and Macau Affairs Office
港澳办那边来消息
They have revoked your candidacy
你候选人的资格已经被取消
Call Beijing. Get some friends to help
打电话去北京，找些朋友帮忙
Let me try
我试试看
Forget it
算了
They even found a dead man to testify against you
他们连一个死了的人也能找到
Everyone knows how loyal Sam was to you
所有人都知道韩琛对你倪家忠心耿耿
Now he's the prosecution's witness It's over
他做污点证人，这官司怎么打?
Sorry. Can't help you
对不起，我帮不了你们
You said there'd be no problem!
你常说可以顺利过渡
Everyone's watching how we will react
大家都很看好我们倪家
What're you going to do?
现在怎么?
What can I do?
你要我怎么办?
Threaten the government?
帐吓中国政府吗?
Don't take it the wrong way
他不是这个意思
We're all in the same boat
不过大家同坐一条船
Time for me to get off then
我下船好了
I'm just a lawyer. Not one of you
我是你们的律师，不是你们的人
I don't intend to sink with you. Sorry
我不想搭上沉船，对不起
Yes
已 下
Sam has a wife and a daughter are in Thailand!
查到韩琛有个老汛和女儿在泰国
It's your call
怎么办你作主
Sis
姐
You and the brothers should take mom...
我想你和大哥、弟弟陪妈妈
... and go to Hawaii for a while
去夏威夷那边住一段时间
Okay. Haven't been there for a while
也好，反正我们很久没过去
Are you going to be all right?
你会不会有事?
I'll be fine
没事…
Sorry I can't help the family
对不起，我没帮上家里什么性
The key thing now is you turn out okay
最重要你没事
Don't be silly. We're a family!
别这样，一家人嘛
Take care of mom!
照顾妈妈
Don't worry. Leave it to us three
放心，交给我们三个
Even with my testimony
我总党得，就算我出庭作证
Hau will only get a couple years
阿孝顶多坐几年牢而已
It's true
那倒是
He'll have to whack you to get life
如果要他终身监禁，除非他杀了你
l have to thank you
这次真的多谢你
Without you
没有你
l could never have come back
我也回不了香港
Save it! I'm busy these days
不跟你谈了，我很忙
Anything you need, ask them
你有什么需要，跟他们说
They'll protect you
这组人负责保护你
Sam!
琛哥
Thanks
谢谢
So, how's it going?
怎样，你好吗?
Good. Been transferred to the CIB
还好，调到刑事情报科
Will be Inspector-in-Training next month
下个月升见习督察了
Did Mary call you...
玛莉姐走的时候…
.. before she left...?
有没有找过你?
Don't be too hard on yourself, Sam
琛哥，节哀顺变吧
Inspector Wong said to find you if 1 needed anything
黄长官说，有事可以找你
Will you really help me?
你会帮我吗?
I thought you wouldn't come
以为你不会来
Why's that?
为什么我不会来?
So here we are
怎么样?
It's been two years
两年了
Because of my father's case
因为与我爸爸的案子有关
you didn't dare to call me for two years?
所以两年都不敢找我?
You couldn't face me?
不敢跟我说话?
Right
已 下
All you need to nail Hau is in the safe
保险箱里，是倪家这两年的犯罪证据
I've organized the files according to dates
我排好档案和日期
Why do you still help me?
为什么还肯帮我?
I'm not helping you
我不是想帮你
l want to keep my promises to SP Luk!
我答应过陆长官的事，我要做到
And I don't want to be a mole any more
还有，我不想再做卧底
Two more years and I'll become the top dog
再做两年，我就成了尖沙咀老大
What for? To end up in prison?
为了什么? 想去坐牢?
Let's bury the past
以前的事我忘了
Just bring me back into the department
拜放你赶快办完这件事，调我回警署
Give me a desk
给我一个舒舒服服的位子
Make sure it has a sea view
我要向海
And don't let me see your face again
但千万别再让我见到你
Don't worry
放心吧
You won't see me any more
你不会见到我的
One more thing
还有
[ couldn't spell some of the words
档案里有些字我不会写
Come find me if you don't understand
你看不惟就来找我
But don't mess up the order
但千万别调乱了次序，我排了很久
I'll kill you if you mess that up!
你调乱了，我宰了你
That's great. Put me out of misery!
那就好了，我的债还清了
You wish!
没那么便宜
Thank you, officer
谢谢你，警察
The trial will start in three days
阿琛，资料齐了，律政司批示三天后上庭
Mr. Hon
韩先生
OCTB!
重案组
Inspector Wong! Sam's gone!
黄长官，韩琛不见了
He escaped through the kitchen
韩琛应该是从厨房通道跑掉的
Who was guarding the kitchen?
谁把守厨房通道?
Sorry, sir
对不起，长官
Sam'd made a call to Thailand...
韩琛走之前
.. before he escaped
打了个电话回泰国
Mr. Ngai
倪先生
What do you want from me?
找我有何吟只?
You called me
是你打电话给我的
So tell me how you can help me
所以你应该告诉我，能帮有我什么忙
Am I right? Sit down
对吧? 坐
Whack me!
杀了我吧
Kill me and it's all over!
杀了我就天下太平
Why should I?
我为什么要杀你?
Haven't done that kind of stuff for ages
我没于这回事很久了
Everything can be negotiated
有话好好说嘛，阿琛
Hong Kong's big enough for us both, Sam
香港这么大
We can even be partners
你愿意的话，我们一起合作
Let's forget about the past
以前的事算了
You will kill me
你一定会杀我
You'll kill me tonight
今晚你就会杀我
But who's gonna take care of your family?
我杀了你，你老婆和女儿怎么办?
Just in!
刚刚收到消息
Hau has Sam's wife and daughter as hostages
倪永孝抓了韩琛在泰国的老婆和女儿
That's his Thai maid!
那是他的泰国帆人
l managed to stay alive all these years
这几年…我死不了
... [have some good buddies in Thailand
我有一个很好的泰国朋友
You want to take this call
你也昕听这个电话
It's from Hawaii
是打去夏威哨的
Your whole family's there
你全家都在那里
My Thai buddies, too
包括我的泰国朋友
Hello! Mr Ngai
倪先生，你好
My boss asked me
我老大叫我
to take good care of your family
好好地招呼你家人
Daddy! Where are you?
答爸…你在哪呀?
Mr. Ngai!
倪先生
Shut up!
住嘴
You'll whack me tonight. I told you so
我说你今晚会杀我的
Put it down, Ngai Wing-Hau!
倪永孝，放下枪
Let him
由他吧
He tried to kill me once before
他以前杀过我…
Let him do it again!
不妨再让他杀一次
Officers
各位警官
After he shoots me...
等会儿他打死我…
..it'll be your call to shoot him or not
开不开枪随便你们
What goes around comes around!
出来跑，迟早要还的
Two questions
两个问题
Did you kill his whole family?
你有没有杀光他全家?
Of course not!
当然没有
My buddies and I were just scaring him!
我和泰国朋友…吓吓他而已
Did you expect me to kill him for you?
你早就料到我会帮你杀他?
Would you believe me if 1 said no?
我说没有，你相信了吗?
l expected to die here
我准备死在这里的
It was my only way
我只有这个办法
Sorry
对不起
Did you know how hard I worked...
你知不知道我用了多少时间
.. to collect tons of evidence...
搜集了多少证据
..to put him away for life?
足够让他在牢房过一辈子
How are you?
你好
The Thai guy, Sam
琛哥，泰国使
Paul!
保罗
Thank you
谢谢
It's all good
那就好了
We're now partners
以后我们合作
Cocaine straight to HK from now on
毒品直接卖到香港
Should ! wrap up the Ngai episode?
侃家的人，我来摆平?
Paul...
保罗…
Maybe we shouldn't go too far
别做得太绝，好吗?
It was pure luck that you bumped into me
以前你碰上我…
Otherwise you would've been killed
算捡回条命
We were destined to be partners...
那枪没打死你
.. when my gun failed to kill you
我们注定是拍档
You can never go too far. Get it?
一定要那样绝
The hand-over ceremony of Hong Kong...
在会展新翼进行的中英交接仪式
... commenced earlier at 11:20
在较早前十一时二十分正式开始
Both countries' anthems were played
两国军乐团亦已经奏出不同的乐章
A British flag
同时一面英国国旗
rose up in the hall
时在会场里面扬扬球起
The ceremony was dignified
仪式虽然庄严
Yet it'd had its share of relaxed moments...
但是在开始前
before its commencement
气氛却非常和谐
When both countries’ marching bands played
在双方军乐团演奏的时候
some Chinese representatives took pictures
有中方代表团的成员正在拍照留念
Prince Charles
而查理斯王子
and Governor Patten were smiling
和港督彭定康到场时亦展露微笑
As the ceremony officially commenced
仪式正式开始
Three British soldiers
三名英军
and three Chinese ones...
和三名手持中国国旗的解放军
.. marched slowly onto the podium
慢慢正步操上主礼台
The Chinese soldiers...
三名解放军
displayed the PRC flag
向中方主礼人展示中国国旗
Following their lead...
随之而来
Three HK Royal Police officers...
三名香港皇家警察
..emerged with
和三名手持特区区旗的
three HK SAR Police officers
特区警察步上礼台
The three SAR officers displayed...
三名特区警察向中方主礼家宾
... the HKSAR flag to the honorable guests
展示香港特区区旗
And now
与此同时
all the guests have risen
全场观礼嘉宾都已纷纷起立
It was exactly midnight
当时钟到达七月一日
The arrival of July 1st, 1997
零时零分之际
The PRC flag rose up...
中国国旗
with the HKSAR flag
和香港特区区旗也徐徐升起
marking the end of the colonial era
见证着一个殖民地统治的结束
It also signified the beginning...
亦同时为历史上
...of the One Country Two Systems policy
一国两制的管治揭开序幕
The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region...
中华人民共和国
... of the People's Republic of China has been established
香港特别行政区正式成立
Okay. It's a deal
已经定了
Come join me
过来跟我
You know what kind of boss is the worst?
跟老大最怕什么，知道吗?
The ugly boss
跟着个样子难看的就坏事了
Look's everything! Look how I shine!
样子很重要，你看我的面油…
What's your name, miss?
小姐，你叫什么名?
I'm Ma... Mary
我叫 Ma… Mary
MAA...
NA. . .
M-A-Y...
NM-A-Y. . .
M-A-R-Y
NM-A-R-Y
Continuous Hell embodies 3 components:
无间有三
Uninterrupted Time, Unlimited Space Boundless Suffering
时无间，空无间，受者无间
Transgressers of the Five Deadly Sins fall into this hell forever
犯五逆界者，永哺此狱
condemned to the ultimate incessant suffering
尽受终极之无间